Preliminary Inventory to the Ronald Reagan subject collection, 1948-2004
Hoover Institution Archives
Ronald Reagan Subject Collection,
1948-2004
75111
47 manuscript boxes, 29 cubic foot boxes, 44 card file boxes, 12 linear feet (70 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Books, clippings, news summaries, other printed matter, lists, indexes, memorabilia, sound recordings, video tapes, and miscellany, relating to the career of Ronald Reagan, his electoral campaigns for governor of California and president of the United States, and his gubernatorial and presidential administrations. Includes recordings of speeches by Reagan, copies of speeches and other public statements, news film of public appearances, microfilm of gubernatorial papers, and some original letters and other original documents. Indexes: Preliminary inventory.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1975.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Books, clippings, news summaries, other printed matter, lists, indexes, memorabilia, sound recordings, video tapes, and miscellany, relating to the career of Ronald Reagan, his electoral campaigns for governor of California and president of the United States, and his gubernatorial and presidential administrations. Includes recordings of speeches by Reagan, copies of speeches and other public statements, news film of public appearances, microfilm of gubernatorial papers, and some original letters and other original documents.
Access Points
Reagan, Ronald; Elections--California; California--Politics and government--1951-; Presidents--United States--Election--1980; Presidents--United States--Election--1984; United States--Politics and government--1981-1989; United States--Politics and government; Phonotapes; Video tapes
Container List
- Ronald Reagan speeches and writings (Box 1-3)
- 1984 presidential campaign miscellanea (Box 4)
- Tapes (Box 5)
- 1980 presidential campaign memorabilia (Box 6-7)
- Radio commentaries, 1976-1979 (Box 8)
- Newspaper columns, 1975-1979 (Box 9)
- Pacific Legal Foundation printed matter (Box 10)
- Political circulars, 1985 (Box 11)
- Public Papers of the Presidents, 1981-1984 (Box 12-17)
- Clippings, 1975-1982 (Box 18-39)
- Photographs (Box 40)
- Ronald Reagan personal documents (Box 41)
- Ronald Reagan foreign policy statements
- Gubernatorial chronology, 1966-1974
- 1976 presidential campaign tape index (Box 42)
  Complete.
- Ronald Reagan miscellanea received from various individuals (Box 43-44)
- Chronology, 1980-1983 (Box 45)
- Gubernatorial administration publications (Box 46)
- Ronald Reagan gubernatorial speeches and task force reports (Box 47-48)
- Memorabilia (Box 49)
- Political circulars, 1979-1984 (Box 50)
- News summaries, 1980-1981 (Box 51-52)
- Clippings, 1979-1985 (Box 53-59)
- California state official telephone directories and gubernatorial administration rosters (Box 60)
- Books about Ronald Reagan (Box 61-64)
- The Quotable Ronald Reagan (Box 65-66)
- Public Papers of the Presidents, 1981-1989 (Box 67-68)
- Tape index, 1975-1976 (Box 69)
  Incomplete. See also Box 42.
- Judicial appointments lists
- Clippings, 1975-early 1976
- Schedules, 1975-early 1976
- Videotapes (Box 70-73)
  - 1963 and early 1980s (Folder 70)
    Also includes manuscript titled "Here's the Rest of Him" by Kent Steffgen.
  - 1981 inauguration (Folder 71)
  - 1970s (Folder 72)
    Includes Republican Convention, 1976
  - Town Meeting of the World, 1967 May 15 (Folder 73)
  - Reagan inauguration (Folder 73)
    1-4 videotapes
  - Count Down to the White House: The Reagan Transition (Folder 73)
  - Campaign '80 (Folder 73)
    Spots regarding Nancy Reagan
- Card files (Box 74-75)
- Audiotapes, 1960s-1970s (Box 76-117)
  - Nation Association of Band Women, Beverly Hilton L.A., campaign speech, 22 May 1965 (Box 76)
  - Salvation Army Banquet, Elks Club, Santa Ana, campaign speech, 24 May 1960 (Box 76)
  - Town Meeting, Glendale, campaign speech, 26 May 1965 (Box 76)
  - Jr. Achievement Banquet, Hacienda Motel, Fresno, campaign speech, 28 May 1965 (Box 76)
  - Republican Womens' Club Annual Memorial Day Dinner, San Gabriel, campaign speech, 30 May 1965 (Box 76)
  - Chamber of Commerce 20th Annual Banquet, South Gate, campaign speech, 1 June 1965 (Box 76)
  - Republican Womens' Federation, Civic Auditorium, Glendale, campaign speech, 3 June 1965 (Box 76)
  - National Association of Newspaper Advertising Executives, San Diego, campaign speech, 23 June 1965 (Box 76)
  - Beverly Hills Rotary Luncheon, campaign speech, 19 July 1965 (Box 76)
  - Delano, campaign speech, 23 July 1965 (Box 76)
  - Pasadena Chamber of Commerce Breakfast, Huntington-Sheraton, campaign speech, 27 July 1965 (Box 76)
  - Riverside County Fundraiser, Jarupa Hills Country Club, fundraiser, 31 July 1965 (Box 76)
  - San Bernadino County Central Committee, Chaffee College Stadium, fundraiser, 14 August 1965 (Box 76)
  - Joint Service Club Meeting, Toluca Lake, campaign speech, 30 August 1965 (Box 76)
  - RR campaign speechpaign Kickoff, press conference, 9 September 1965 (Box 76)
  - American Association of University Women, El Centro, campaign speech, 9 September 1965 (Box 76)
  - Coachella Valley Teachers' Meeting, Indio, campaign speech, 10 September 1965 (Box 76)
  - Republican Association, Sun City, Riverside County, campaign speech, 10 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - National Secretary's Association, union oil Center, L.A., campaign speech, 11 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - Joint Kiwanis Luncheon, Knollwood Country Club, campaign speech, 14 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - Aerojet General Management Club, Lakewood Country Club, campaign speech, 14 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - Airport Business and Professional Womens' Association, International Hotel, L.A., campaign speech, 16 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - L.A. Host Lions Club, Biltmore Hotel, campaign speech, 17 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - Public Relations Society of America. Orange County Chapter, Santa Ana, campaign speech, 20 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - 56th Annual Dinner of the United Republicans of California, campaign speech, 21 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - Stanislaus County Fundraising Dinner, Modesto, fundraiser, 22 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - Real Estate Luncheon, San Jose, campaign speech, 23 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - Masonic Lodges Speech (Constitution Day Observance), Foothill College, L.A., campaign speech, 23 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - California Employment Agencies Association Luncheon, Palo Alto, campaign speech, 24 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - Womens' Breakfast Club of Berkeley, campaign speech, 24 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - New Haven Connecticut, press conference and speech, 28 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - New England Federation of Republican Women, campaign speech, 29 September 1965 (Box 77)
  - Knights of Columbus, Oxnard, campaign speech, 6 October 1965 (Box 77)
  - Channel City Club, Santa Barbara, campaign speech, 7 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Holy Name Society, Coalinga, campaign speech, 9 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Fallbrook Bar-B-Que, Live Oak Park, campaign speech, 11 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Republican Association Luncheon, Biltmore Bowl, L.A., campaign speech, 13 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Fleet Officers' Wives Luncheon, Terminal Island Officer Club, campaign speech, 14 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Oilwell Drilling Contractors, Biltmore Hotel, L.A., campaign speech, 14 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Rotary Club, Statler Hilton, L.A., campaign speech, 15 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - L.A. County Medical Society, campaign speech, 15 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - County Employees' Convention, San Bernardino, campaign speech, 16 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Laguna Beach Federated Women's Luncheon, Newporter Inn, campaign speech, 18 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Council of Richmond Industries, El Cerrito, campaign speech, 21 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Whittier College, First Friends Church, campaign speech, 26 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Kiwanis Joint Luncheon, Walnut Valley Country Club, campaign speech, 26 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Joint Real Estate Board, El Cortez Hotel, San Diego, campaign speech, 27 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Orange County Economics Development Program, campaign speech, 28 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Alhambra Junior Chamber of Commerce, Huntington-Sheratn Hotel, L.A., campaign speech, 29 October 1965 (Box 78)
  - Financial Executives' Institute, Biltmore Hotel, L.A., campaign speech, 1 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - Edison Electric Executives' Institute, Ambassador Hotel, Los Angeles, campaign speech, 1 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - South Orange County Republican Womens' Federation, San Juan Capistrano, fundraiser, 2 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - Rossmore Community Leisure World, Walnut Creek, campaign speech, 6 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - Sonoma County Farm Bureau Annual Dinner, Citrus Fair, Cloverdale, campaign speech, 6 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - North Lake Tahoe Republican Women, Olympic Village, Squaw Valley, campaign speech, 8 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - Colusa, Glenn, Sutter, and Yuba Counties Precinct Workers' Rally, Yuba-Sutter Fairgrounds, campaign speech, 9 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - Kings County Fundraising Dinner, Willetts Hangar, Hanford, fundraiser, 10 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - Pacific Palisades Republican Club, Paul Revere Jr. High School, L.A., campaign speech, 11 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - Redondo Beach Chamber of Commerce, L.A., campaign speech, 11 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - Palos Verdes Peninsula Rotary Club Luncheon, L.A., campaign speech, 11 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - Los Feliz Republican Womens' Federation, Masonic Temple, campaign speech, 12 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - Tulare Industrial Management Luncheon, Visalia, campaign speech, 19 November 1965 (Box 79)
  - Harbor Area Young Republican Fundraising Dinner, Newporter Inn, fundraiser, 3 December 1965 (Box 79)
  - California Republican League, Biltmore Hotel, L.A., campaign speech, 4 December 1965 (Box 79)
  - 13th District Republican Co-ord. Council Dinner, Holiday Bowl, Hayward, campaign speech, 8 December 1965 (Box 79)
  - Marin County GOP County Committee Fundraiser, San Rafael, fundraiser, 9 December 1965 (Box 79)
  - Chico-Paradise Realty Board, Elks Lodge, campaign speech, 9 December 1965 (Box 79)
  - Santa Cruz Fundraiser, fundraiser, 10 December 1965 (Box 80)
  - San Mateo County Chamber of Commerce Luncheon, San Mateo, campaign speech, 10 December 1965 (Box 80)
  - Personal Industrial Relations Association, Statler Hilton, Los Angeles, campaign speech, 15 December 1965 (Box 80)
  - campaign speechpaign '66 (Agriculture), campaign speech, 1966 (Box 80)
  - RR for Governor campaign speechpaign Announcement Day, Statler Hilton, Los Angeles, press conference, 4 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - Ronald Regean Special - Kickoff talk, campaign speech, 4 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - San Diego's Womens' Federation Convention, Hilton Inn, San Diego, campaign speech, 7 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - Eagle Scout Award, Chula Vista Jr. High School, San Diego, campaign speech, 7 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - Young Married Group Meeting, Church Center Theater, campaign speech, 9 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - Taped for ABC-TV viewing, press conference, 9 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - Associated Chamber of Commerce, West Valley, campaign speech, 10 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - Optomist Lion-Rotary Club, West Los Angeles, campaign speech, 12 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - Laguna Road PTA Meeting, campaign speech, 18 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - Merced Fundraiser, GOP Central Committee, fundraiser, 24 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - East Bay Alliance, campaign speech, 24 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - First Hebrew Congregation Temple Dinner, Oakland, campaign speech, 25 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - Healdsburg Chamber of Commerce, campaign speech, 26 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - Research Institute for Government, Whittier High School Auditorium, Whittier, campaign speech, 28 January 1966 (Box 80)
  - Audiotapes, undescribed (Box 81-117)
- Videotapes (3) (Box 118)
- Videotapes, Ronald Reagan Gubernatorial papers, microfilm reels (Box 119-120)
  From Simi Valley, Calif.
- Audiovisual material and videotapes, 1960s-1970s (Shelf On shelf)